which seems like a fairly humble vocation.
وهي ما تبدو وكأنها مهنة متواضعة تمامًا.
I know a lot about pots.
أعرف الكثير عن الأواني الفخارية.
I've spent about 15 years making them.
لقد قضيت حوالي 15 عامًا في صناعتها.
One of the things that really excites me in my artistic practice
وإن أحد الأشياء التي أسرتني حقًا في ممارستي الفنية
and being trained as a potter
وفي كوني مدرَّبًا كخزاف
is that you very quickly learn how to make great things out of nothing;
هي أنك تتعلم بسرعة كيف تصنع أشياء رائعة من العدم؛
that I spent a lot of time at my wheel with mounds of clay trying stuff;
حتى أني قضيت الكثير من الوقت على دولابي مع أكوام من الطين أجرب صناعة أشياء؛
and that the limitations of my capacity, my ability,
وحتى أن حدود طاقتي الإنتاجية وقدرتي
was based on my hands and my imagination;
كانت تعتمد على يديّ وخيالي؛
that if I wanted to make a really nice bowl
حتى أنني إن أردت صناعة قدر جميل
and I didn't know how to make a foot yet,
ولم أكن أعلم كيف أصنع القاعدة بعد،
I would have to learn how to make a foot;
يكون عليّ أن أتعلم كيف أصنع القاعدة؛
that that process of learning has been very, very helpful to my life.
حتى أن عملية التعلم تلك قد كانت مفيدة للغاية في حياتي.
I feel like, as a potter,
أشعر بأنه، كخزّاف،
you also start to learn how to shape the world.
فإنك تبدأ أيضًا بتعلم كيفية تشكيل العالم.
There have been times in my artistic capacity
كانت هناك أوقات خلال إنتاجي الفني
that I wanted to reflect
حين أردت الإشارة
on other really important moments
إلى لحظات أخرى مهمة حقًا
in the history of the U.S., the history of the world
في تاريخ الولايات المتحدة، تاريخ العالم
where tough things happened,
الذي حدثت فيه أعظم الأمور،
but how do you talk about tough ideas
ولكن كيف تتحدث عن الأفكار العظيمة
without separating people from that content?
دون فصل الأشخاص عن ذلك المحتوى؟
Could I use art like these old, discontinued firehoses from Alabama,
هل بإمكاني استخدام الفن كمحطات الإطفاء الموقوفة هذه في ألاباما؟
to talk about the complexities of a moment of civil rights in the '60s?
الحديث عن تعقيدات لحظة للحقوق المدنية في الستينات؟
Is it possible to talk about my father and I doing labor projects?
هل من الممكن الحديث عنا، أنا وأبي، ونحن نقوم بمشاريع عمل؟
My dad was a roofer, construction guy, he owned small businesses,
كان أبي بنَّاء أسقف، عامل بناء، امتلك أعمالًا صغيرة،
and at 80, he was ready to retire and his tar kettle was my inheritance.
وفي الثمانينات، كان جاهزًا للتقاعد وكان ميراثي سخان قطران.
Now, a tar kettle doesn't sound like much of an inheritance. It wasn't.
الآن، فإن سخان القطران لا يبدو كميراث كبير. لم يكن كذلك.
It was stinky and it took up a lot of space in my studio,
كان كريه الرائحة واحتل مساحة كبيرة من معملي،
but I asked my dad if he would be willing to make some art with me,
ولكني سألت والدي إن كان على استعداد لعمل بعض الفن معي،
if we could reimagine this kind of nothing material
إن كان باستطاعتنا إعادة تخيل هذا النوع من المادة التي لا تذكر
as something very special.
كشيء خاص جدًا.
And by elevating the material and my dad's skill,
وبواسطة رفع المادة ومهارة أبي،
could we start to think about tar just like clay, in a new way,
هل بإمكاننا البدء في التفكير بشأن القطران كما الطين، بطريقة جديدة،
shaping it differently, helping us to imagine what was possible?
نشكله بشكل مختلف، يساعدنا على تخيل ما كان ممكنًا؟
After clay, I was then kind of turned on to lots of different kinds of materials,
بعد الطين، كنت متحمسًا للعديد من المواد المتنوعة،
and my studio grew a lot because I thought, well,
وكبُر المعمل خاصتي كثيرًا لأنني اعتقدت
it's not really about the material, it's about our capacity to shape things.
أنه في الواقع ليس بشأن المادة، بل بشأن مقدرتنا على تشكيل الأشياء.
I became more and more interested in ideas
أصبحت مهتمًا أكثر بالأفكار
and more and more things that were happening just outside my studio.
وبأشياء أكثر وأكثر كانت تحدث خارج معملي.
Just to give you a little bit of context, I live in Chicago.
لأقرب لكم الصورة، أعيش في شيكاغو.
I live on the South Side now. I'm a West Sider.
أسكن في الجانب الجنوبي الآن. أنا أنتمي هناك.
For those of you who are not Chicagoans, that won't mean anything,
ولمن منكم ليس من شيكاغو، فهذا لن يعني شيئًا،
but if I didn't mention that I was a West Sider,
ولكن إن لم أذكر أني من الجانب الجنوبي،
there would be a lot of people in the city that would be very upset.
سيكون الكثير من الأشخاص في المدينة مستاءين جدًا.
The neighborhood that I live in is Grand Crossing.
الحارة التي أسكن فيها هي غراند كروسنغ.
It's a neighborhood that has seen better days.
إنها حارة قد شهدت أيامًا أفضل.
It is not a gated community by far.
إنه ليس مجتمعًا منغلقًا على نفسه كثيرًا.
There is lots of abandonment in my neighborhood,
هناك الكثير من الهجرة في حارتي،
and while I was kind of busy making pots and busy making art
وبينما كنت مشغولًا نوعًا ما بصناعة الخزف وصناعة الفن
and having a good art career,
وامتلاك وظيفة فن جيدة،
there was all of this stuff that was happening
كانت كل هذه الأمور تحدث
just outside my studio.
مباشرة خارج معملي.
All of us know about failing housing markets
كلنا يعلم عن الهبوط في سوق الإسكان
and the challenges of blight,
وتحديات الجفاف،
and I feel like we talk about it with some of our cities more than others,
وأشعر بأننا نتحدث بهذا الشأن عن بعض مدننا أكثر من المدن الأخرى،
but I think a lot of our U.S. cities and beyond
ولكنني أعتقد أن العديد من مدننا في الولايات المتحدة وأبعد
have the challenge of blight,
تواجه تحدي الجفاف،
abandoned buildings that people no longer know what to do anything with.
منازل متروكة حتى أن الناس لم يعودوا يعرفون ما يفعلون بها.
And so I thought, is there a way that I could start to think
ولذا فكرت، هل هناك طريقة أستطيع من خلالها البدء بالتفكير
about these buildings as an extension or an expansion of my artistic practice?
بشأن هذه المباني كامتداد أو توسع لممارستي الفنية؟
And that if I was thinking along with other creatives --
وفيما لو كنت أفكر مع مبدعين آخرين --
architects, engineers, real estate finance people --
معماريين ومهندسين وممولين عقاريين --
that us together might be able to kind of think
بأننا ربما نقدر معًا على التفكير نوعًأ ما
in more complicated ways about the reshaping of cities.
بطرق أكثر تعقيدًا لإعادة تشكيل المدن.
And so I bought a building.
ولذا قمت بشراء أحد المبانى.
The building was really affordable.
كان سعر البناية في متناول اليد.
We tricked it out.
قمنا بتزيينها.
We made it as beautiful as we could to try to just get some activity happening
جعلناها بأجمل ما يمكننا لمحاولة الحصول على بعض النشاط
on my block.
يحدث في مربعي السكني.
Once I bought the building for about 18,000 dollars,
فور شرائي البناية بحوالي 18,000 دولار،
I didn't have any money left.
لم يتبق لدي مال.
So I started sweeping the building as a kind of performance.
لذا بدأت بكنس البناية كنوع من الأداء.
This is performance art, and people would come over,
هذا فن أدائي، وبدأ الناس يأتون،
and I would start sweeping.
وبدأت الكنس.
Because the broom was free and sweeping was free.
ولأن المكنسة كانت مجانية والتكنيس مجانيًا،
It worked out.
فقد نجح الأمر.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But we would use the building, then, to stage exhibitions, small dinners,
ولكننا نريد استخدام البناية، عندها، لإقامة المعارض والعشاءات الصغيرة،
and we found that that building on my block, Dorchester --
ووجدنا أن تلك البناية في مربعي السكني، دورتشستر --
we now referred to the block as Dorchester projects --
أصبحنا نطلق عليها الآن اسم مشاريع دورتشستر --
that in a way that building became a kind of gathering site
أنها بطريقة ما أصبحت كمكان للتجمع
for lots of different kinds of activity.
للعديد من النشاطات المختلفة.
We turned the building into what we called now the Archive House.
قمنا بتحويل البناية إلى ما ندعوه الآن باسم بيت الأرشيف.
The Archive House would do all of these amazing things.
سيفعل بيت الأرشيف كل هذه الأشياء المذهلة.
Very significant people in the city and beyond
أناس مهمون جدًا من المدينة وغيرها
would find themselves in the middle of the hood.
سيجدون أنفسهم في وسط الحي.
And that's when I felt like
وهذا عندما شعرت بأنه
maybe there was a relationship between my history with clay
ربما هناك علاقة بين ماضيّ مع الطين
and this new thing that was starting to develop,
وهذا الشيء الجديد الذي بدأ يتطور،
that we were slowly starting
أننا بدأنا ببطء
to reshape how people imagined the South Side of the city.
إعادة تشكيل كيفية تخيل الناس للجانب الجنوبي من المدينة.
One house turned into a few houses,
تحول منزل إلى بضعة منازل،
and we always tried to suggest
وحاولنا دومًا أن نقترح
that not only is creating a beautiful vessel important,
ليس فقط أن صناعة وعاء جميل هو أمر مهم،
but the contents of what happens in those buildings is also very important.
بل إن محتويات ما يحدث لهذه البنايات هو أيضًا مهم جدًا.
So we were not only thinking about development,
لذا فلم نكن نفكر بشأن التطوير فحسب،
but we were thinking about the program,
بل كنا نفكر بشأن البرنامج،
thinking about the kind of connections that could happen
نفكر بشأن نوع التواصل الذي من الممكن حدوثه
between one house and another, between one neighbor and another.
بين المنزل والمنزل الآخر، بين الجار والجار الآخر.
This building became what we call the Listening House,
أصبحت هذه البناية ما ندعوه ببيت الاستماع،
and it has a collection of discarded books
وكانت تحوي مجموعة من الكتب التي تم الاستغناء عنها
from the Johnson Publishing Corporation,
من شركة جونسون للنشر،
and other books from an old bookstore that was going out of business.
وبعض الكتب من مكتبة قديمة كانت توشك على الإفلاس.
I was actually just wanting to activate these buildings as much as I could
أردت في الحقيقة تفعيل هذه البنايات بقدر استطاعتي لا أكثر
with whatever and whoever would join me.
بمساعدة أي شيء وأي شخص يود الانضمام إليّ.
In Chicago, there's amazing building stock.
في شيكاغو، هناك منازل مذهلة للبيع.
This building, which had been the former crack house on the block,
هذه البناية، والتي سبق أن كانت المنزل المتصدع في مربعي السكني،
and when the building became abandoned,
عندما أصبحت مهجورة،
it became a great opportunity to really imagine what else could happen there.
فإنها أصبحت فرصة عظيمة لنتخيل حقيقة ما نستطيع فعله بها.
So this space we converted into what we call Black Cinema House.
إذًا قمنا بتحويل هذه المساحة إلى ما ندعوه بيت السينما السوداء.
Black Cinema House was an opportunity in the hood to screen films
كان بيت السينما السوداء يمثل فرصة للحي لعرض أفلام
that were important and relevant to the folk who lived around me,
مهمة وذات صلة بالسكان الذين عاشوا حولي،
that if we wanted to show an old Melvin Van Peebles film, we could.
حتى أننا إن أردنا عرض فيلم قديم لميلفن فان بيبلز، كان باستطاعتنا ذلك.
If we wanted to show "Car Wash," we could.
إذا أردنا عرض فيلم "كار ووش"، كان باستطاعتنا ذلك.
That would be awesome.
سيكون ذلك ممتعًا.
The building we soon outgrew,
كبرت البناية مع الزمن،
and we had to move to a larger space.
وكان علينا الانتقال منها إلى مساحة أكبر.
Black Cinema House, which was made from just a small piece of clay,
كان على بيت السينما السوداء، الذي أنشىء من قطعة صغيرة من الطين،
had to grow into a much larger piece of clay, which is now my studio.
أن يكبُر إلى قطعة كبيرة من الطين، وهو الآن معملي.
What I realized was that for those of you who are zoning junkies,
ما أدركته هو أنه لمن يدمن على التقسيم،
that some of the things that I was doing
فبعض الأشياء التي كنت أفعلها
in these buildings that had been left behind,
بهذه البنايات التي تم هجرها،
they were not the uses by which the buildings were built,
لم تكن الاستخدامات التي بُنيت هذه البنايات لأجلها،
and that there are city policies that say,
وأن هناك سياسات للمدينة تقول:
"Hey, a house that is residential needs to stay residential."
"مهلًا، المنزل السكنيّ ينبغي أن يبقى سكنيًا".
But what do you do in neighborhoods when ain't nobody interested in living there?
ولكن ماذا تفعلون بأحياء عندما لا يرغب أحد بالسكن فيها؟
That the people who have the means to leave have already left?
أن الناس الذين يقدرون على الرحيل قاموا بالرحيل بالفعل؟
What do we do with these abandoned buildings?
ماذا تفعلون بهذه البنايات المهجورة؟
And so I was trying to wake them up using culture.
وهكذا كنت أحاول إيقاظهم باستخدام الثقافة.
We found that that was so exciting for folk,
وجدنا أن ذلك كان مثيرًا جدًا للناس،
and people were so responsive to the work, that we had to then find bigger buildings.
وأن الناس كانوا متجاوبين جدًا مع العمل، واحتجنا بعدها للعثور على بنايات أكبر.
By the time we found bigger buildings,
وبحلول الوقت، وجدنا بنايات أكبر،
there was, in part, the resources necessary to think about those things.
كانت تتوفر، جزئيًا، الموارد الضرورية للتفكير بشأن هذه الأمور.
In this bank that we called the Arts Bank, it was in pretty bad shape.
وفي هذا البنك الذي أسميناه بنك الفنون، كان الوضع سيئا إلى حد ما.
There was about six feet of standing water.
كان هناك حوالي ستة أماكن معرضة للسقوط من المياه الراكدة.
It was a difficult project to finance,
كان مشروعًا يصعب تمويله،
because banks weren't interested in the neighborhood
لأن البنوك لم تكن مهتمة بالحيّ،
because people weren't interested
لأن الناس لم يكونوا مهتمين بالحيّ،
because nothing had happened there.
لأن لا شيء حدث هناك.
It was dirt. It was nothing. It was nowhere.
كان المكان قذرًا. كان لا شيء. كان في اللامكان.
And so we just started imagining, what else could happen in this building?
ومن هنا بدأنا نتخيل، ما الذي يمكن حدوثه في هذه البناية؟
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And so now that the rumor of my block has spread,
والآن بما أن الإشاعة عن حيي قد انتشرت،
and lots of people are starting to visit,
وبدأ الكثير من الناس بالزيارة،
we've found that the bank can now be a center
وجدنا أن البنك يستطيع الآن أن يكون مركزًا
for exhibition, archives, music performance,
للمعرض والأرشيف والأنشطة الموسيقية،
and that there are people who are now interested
وأن هناك أشخاصًا مهتمين الآن
in being adjacent to those buildings because we brought some heat,
بالقرب من هذه البنايات لأننا أعطينا قليلًا من الحرارة
that we kind of made a fire.
التي صنعناها نوعًا ما من نار.
One of the archives that we'll have there is this Johnson Publishing Corporation.
إحدى دور الأرشيف التي ستتواجد لدينا هناك هي شركة جونسون للنشر هذه.
We've also started to collect memorabilia from American history,
وقد بدأنا أيضًا بجمع مواد تذكارية من التاريخ الأمريكي،
from people who live or have lived in that neighborhood.
من أناس يعيشون أو عاشوا في ذلك الحيّ.
Some of these images are degraded images of black people,
بعض هذه الصور هي صور لأشخاص سود تم التقليل من قيمتها،
kind of histories of very challenging content,
نوع من التاريخ بمحتوى على قدر من التحدي،
and where better than a neighborhood
وأين يوجد مكان أفضل من الحيّ
with young people who are constantly asking themselves about their identity
لشباب يسألون أنفسهم باستمرار عن هويتهم
to talk about some of the complexities
للحديث عن بعض تعقيدات
of race and class?
العرق والطبقة الاجتماعية؟
In some ways, the bank represents a hub,
ببعض الحالات، يشكل البنك مركزًا،
that we're trying to create a pretty hardcore node of cultural activity,
حيث أننا نحاول إنشاء ملتقى مركزي للنشاط الثقافي،
and that if we could start to make multiple hubs
وأننا في حال استطعنا بدء عمل مراكز متعددة
and connect some cool green stuff around there,
ووصلناها ببعض من الأشياء الخضراء الممتعة هناك،
that the buildings that we've purchased and rehabbed,
أن البنايات التي سبق واشتريناها وأصلحناها،
which is now around 60 or 70 units,
وهي الآن حوالي 60 أو 70 وحدة،
that if we could land miniature Versailles on top of that,
أننا إن استطعنا إضافة نسخة مصغرة من فرساي
and connect these buildings by a beautiful greenbelt --
وربط هذه البنايات بحزام أخضر جميل --
(Applause) --
(تصفيق) --
that this place where people never wanted to be
أن هذا المكان الذي لم يرغب الناس بالتواجد فيه
would become an important destination
سيصبح وجهة مهمة
for folk from all over the country and world.
للناس من جميع أنحاء البلاد والعالم.
In some ways, it feels very much like I'm a potter,
بطريقة ما، ذلك يشعرني جدًا بأنني خزّاف،
that we tackle the things that are at our wheel,
أننا نمسك بالأشياء التي على دولابنا،
we try with the skill that we have
نحاول مع المهارة التي نمتلكها
to think about this next bowl that I want to make.
أن نفكر بشأن الوعاء القادم الذي سأقوم بصناعته.
And it went from a bowl to a singular house to a block to a neighborhood
وهو تحول من وعاء إلى منزل واحد إلى مربع سكني إلى حيّ
to a cultural district to thinking about the city,
إلى منطقة ثقافية للتفكير بشأن المدينة،
and at every point, there were things that I didn't know that I had to learn.
وفي كل مرحلة، كانت هناك أشياء لم أكن أعلم أن عليّ تعلمها.
I've never learned so much about zoning law in my life.
لم يسبق لي في حياتي أن تعلمت الكثير عن قانون تقسيم المناطق.
I never thought I'd have to.
لم يسبق لي أن اعتقدت أن عليّ فعل ذلك.
But as a result of that, I'm finding that there's not just room
ولكن وكنتيجة لذلك الأمر، أجد أنه ليس هناك فقط متسع
for my own artistic practice,
من أجل ممارستي الفنية،
there's room for a lot of other artistic practices.
بل إن هناك متسع للكثير من الممارسات الفنية الأخرى.
So people started asking us,
إذًا بدأ الناس يسألوننا:
"Well, Theaster, how are you going to go to scale?"
"حسنًا يا ثياستر، كيف ستتوسع؟"
and, "What's your sustainability plan?"
و "ما خطة الاستدامة خاصتك؟"
(Laughter) (Applause)
(ضحك) (تصفيق)
And what I found was that I couldn't export myself,
وما وجدته هو أنني لم أستطع تصدير نفسي،
that what seems necessary in cities like Akron, Ohio,
أن ما يبدو ضروريًا في مدن كآكرون وأوهايو
and Detroit, Michigan, and Gary, Indiana,
وديترويت وميشيغان وغاري وإنديانا
is that there are people in those places who already believe in those places,
هو أن هناك أناس في هذه الأماكن يؤمنون فعلًا بها،
that are already dying to make those places beautiful,
يموتون فعلًا من أجل جعلها جميلة،
and that often, those people who are passionate about a place
وأنه غالبًا، هؤلاء الناس الشغفون بالمكان
are disconnected from the resources necessary to make cool things happen,
لا يملكون الموارد الضرورية لصناعة أشياء مذهلة،
or disconnected from a contingency of people
أو ليسوا على تواصل مع فريق من الأشخاص
that could help make things happen.
الذين يستطيعون صناعة أشياء مذهلة.
So now, we're starting to give advice around the country
الآن، فقد بدأنا بإسداء النصيحة في أرجاء البلاد
on how to start with what you got,
حول كيفية البدء بما تمتلكونه،
how to start with the things that are in front of you,
كيفية البدء بأشياء موجودة أمامكم،
how to make something out of nothing,
كيفية صناعة أشياء من العدم،
how to reshape your world at a wheel or at your block
كيفية إعادة تشكيل عالمكم من على دولاب أو في مربعكم السكنيّ
or at the scale of the city.
أو على نطاق المدينة.
Thank you so much.
شكرًا جزيلًا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
June Cohen: Thank you. So I think many people watching this
جون كوهين: شكرًا لك. إذًا أعتقد أن الكثيرين ممن يشاهدون هذا
will be asking themselves the question you just raised at the end:
سيسألون أنفسهم ذات السؤال الذي طرحته في النهاية:
How can they do this in their own city?
كيف بإمكانهم أن يفعلوا هذا في مدينتهم؟
You can't export yourself.
لا يمكنك أن تصدر نفسك.
Give us a few pages out of your playbook about what someone who is inspired
أعطنا بعض الصفحات من تجربتك حول ما يستطيع شخص ملهم بشأن مدينته
about their city can do to take on projects like yours?
أن يفعله لتنفيذ مشاريع كمشروعك؟
Theaster Gates: One of the things I've found that's really important
ثياستر غيتس: إن أحد الأشياء التي وجدتها مهمة حقًا
is giving thought to not just the kind of individual project,
هو التفكير ليس في مشروع واحد فحسب،
like an old house,
كمنزل قديم،
but what's the relationship between an old house,
ولكن ما العلاقة بين منزل قديم
a local school, a small bodega,
ومدرسة محلية وحانة صغيرة
and is there some kind of synergy between those things?
وهل هناك نوع ما من الانسجام بين هذه الأشياء؟
Can you get those folk talking?
هل بإمكانكم جعل هذه الأشياء تتحدث؟
I've found that in cases where neighborhoods have failed,
قد وجدت ذلك في حالات لم تنجح فيها الأحياء،
they still often have a pulse.
لا زالت تملك نبضًا.
How do you identify the pulse in that place, the passionate people,
كيف تحدد النبض في ذلك المكان، في الناس الشغوفين،
and then how do you get folk who have been fighting,
وكيف تجعل الأشخاص الذين كانوا يتقاتلون،
slogging for 20 years, reenergized about the place that they live?
يتناحرون على مدى 20 سنة، مفعمين بشأن المكان الذي يعيشون فيه؟
And so someone has to do that work.
إذًا هناك أحد ما عليه أن يقوم بذلك العمل.
If I were a traditional developer, I would be talking about buildings alone,
إن كنتُ مطورًا تقليديًا، لكنت أتحدث عن البنايات وحدها،
and then putting a "For Lease" sign in the window.
ثم أضع لافتة "للإيجار" على النافذة.
I think that you actually have to curate more than that,
أعتقد أن بإمكانكم حقًا أن تقوموا بفعل أكثر من ذلك،
that there's a way in which you have to be mindful about,
أن هناك طريقة عليكم أن تكونوا يقظين بشأنها،
what are the businesses that I want to grow here?
ما الأعمال التي أود إقامتها هنا؟
And then, are there people who live in this place
ثم هل هناك أناس ممن يسكنون هذا المكان
who want to grow those businesses with me?
يرغبون بإقامة أعمال معي؟
Because I think it's not just a cultural space or housing;
لأنني أعتقد أنها ليست مساحة ثقافية أو مشروع إسكان؛
there has to be the recreation of an economic core.
يجب أن يكون هناك نوع من إعادة البناء للجوهر الاقتصادي.
So thinking about those things together feels right.
إذًا فالتفكير بشأن هذه الأشياء معًا يبدو صحيحًا.
JC: It's hard to get people to create the spark again
جون كوهين: من الصعب جذب الناس لإنشاء شرارة ثانية
when people have been slogging for 20 years.
عندما كان الناس متناحرين لـ 20 سنة.
Are there any methods you've found that have helped break through?
هل هناك ثمة طرق وجدتها وساعدتك في تخطي الأمر؟
TG: Yeah, I think that now there are lots of examples
ثياستر غيتس: نعم، أعتقد أنه الآن يوجد العديد من الأمثلة
of folk who are doing amazing work,
لأشخاص يقومون بعمل رائع،
but those methods are sometimes like, when the media is constantly saying
ولكن هذه الطرق أحيانًا تبدو وكأنها، عندما تستمر وسائل الإعلام بالقول
that only violent things happen in a place,
أن الأشياء العنيفة وحدها تحدث في المكان،
then based on your skill set and the particular context,
إذًا فاعتمادًا على مجموعة مهاراتكم والبيئة المحددة،
what are the things that you can do in your neighborhood
ما الأشياء التي يمكنكم فعلها في حيِّكم
to kind of fight some of that?
لمحاربة ذلك نوعًا ما؟
So I've found that if you're a theater person,
إذًا وجدتُ أنك إن كنت رجل مسرح،
you have outdoor street theater festivals.
فلديك مهرجانات مسرحية في الشارع.
In some cases, we don't have the resources in certain neighborhoods
في بعض الحالات، لا نمتلك الموارد في أحياء معينة
to do things that are a certain kind of splashy,
لفعل أشياء لامعة نوعًا ما،
but if we can then find ways of making sure that people
لكن إن كان بوسعنا إيجاد طرق للتأكد من أن الأشخاص
who are local to a place,
الذين يعرفون المكان جيدا،
plus people who could be supportive of the things that are happening locally,
بالإضافة إلى أناس يستطيعون أن يكونوا داعمين لأشياء تحدث محليًا،
when those people get together,
عندما يجتمع هؤلاء الأشخاص،
I think really amazing things can happen.
أعتقد أنه من الممكن أن تحدث أشياء رائعة.
JC: So interesting.
جون كوهين: مثير للغاية.
And how can you make sure that the projects you're creating
وكيف يمكنك التأكد من أن المشاريع التي تقيمها
are actually for the disadvantaged
هي بالفعل للمحرومين
and not just for the sort of vegetarian indie movie crowd
وليست من أجل نوع من جمهور لا يشاهد إلا الأفلام الهندية
that might move in to take advantage of them.
ربما ينتقل للسكن هناك ليستغل هذه المشاريع.
TG: Right on. So I think this is where it starts to get into the thick weeds.
ثياستر غيتس: أحسنتِ. إذًا أعتقد أن هذا حيث تبدأ الأمور باتخاذ منحنى سيىء.
JC: Let's go there. TG: Right now, Grand Crossing
جون كوهين: دعنا نذهب هناك. ثياستر غيتس: حاليًا، غراند كروسينغ
is 99 percent black, or at least living,
تبلغ نسبة سكانها من السود 99%، أو على الأقل يعيشون،
and we know that maybe who owns property in a place
ونعلم أنه ربما أن من له أملاك في المكان
is different from who walks the streets every day.
مختلف عن الذين يمرون في الشوارع كل يوم.
So it's reasonable to say that Grand Crossing is already
لذا فمن المعقول القول بأن غراند كروسينغ بالفعل
in the process of being something different than it is today.
هي في مرحلة التغير إلى شيء مختلف عما هي عليه اليوم.
But are there ways to think about housing trusts or land trusts
ولكن هل هناك طرق للتفكير بشأن اتحادات للإسكان أو اتحادات للأراضي
or a mission-based development
أو تنمية قائمة على البعثة
that starts to protect some of the space that happens,
والتي تبدأ بحماية بعض المساحة التي تحدث،
because when you have 7,500 empty lots in a city,
لأنكم عندما تملكون 7,500 قطعة أرض فارغة في المدينة،
you want something to happen there,
فإنكم تريدون شيئًا ما أن يحدث هناك،
but you need entities that are not just interested in the development piece,
ولكنكم تحتاجون كيانات ليست مهتمة بقطعة التطوير فحسب،
but entities that are interested in the stabilization piece,
بل كيانات مهتمة بقطعة الاستقرار،
and I feel like often the developer piece is really motivated,
وأشعر بأنه غالبًا تكون قطعة المطوِّر محفزة بالفعل،
but the other work of a kind of neighborhood consciousness,
ولكن العمل الآخر من نوع الوعي بحقوق الجار،
that part doesn't live anymore.
ذلك الجزء لم يعد يعيش أبدًا.
So how do you start to grow up important watchdogs
إذًا كيف تبدأ بتربية كلاب حراسة مهمة
that ensure that the resources that are made available
تتأكد من أن الموارد التي تُصبح متاحة
to new folk that are coming in
للناس الجدد القادمين
are also distributed to folk who have lived in a place for a long time.
يتم توزيعها أيضًا على الناس الذين عاشوا في المكان لفترة طويلة.
JC: That makes so much sense. One more question:
جون كوهين: ذلك منطقي جدًا. سؤال آخر إضافي:
You make such a compelling case for beauty and the importance of beauty and the arts.
أنت تصنع حالة قهرية للجمال وأهمية الجمال والفنون.
There would be others who would argue that funds would be better spent
سيكون هناك آخرون يقولون بأن الأموال سيكون من الأفضل صرفها
on basic services for the disadvantaged.
على الخدمات الأساسية للمحرومين.
How do you combat that viewpoint, or come against it?
كيف تدحض وجهة النظر هذه أو تواجهها؟
TG: I believe that beauty is a basic service.
ثياستر غيتس: أؤمن بأن الجمال خدمة أساسية.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Often what I have found is that when there are resources
غالبًا فإن ما وجدته هو أنه عندما توجد الموارد
that have not been made available to certain under-resourced cities
التي لم تكن متوفرة عند مدن معينة قليلة الموارد
or neighborhoods or communities,
أو عند أحياء أو مجتمعات،
that sometimes culture is the thing that helps to ignite,
فإن الثقافة أحيانًا هي الشيء الذي يساعد في إطلاق الشعلة،
and that I can't do everything,
وأنني لا أستطيع فعل شيء،
but I think that there's a way in which if you can start with culture
لكني أعتقد بأن هناك طريق من خلالها إن استطعتم البدء مع الثقافة
and get people kind of reinvested in their place,
واستثمار الناس نوعًا ما مرة أخرى في مكانهم،
other kinds of adjacent amenities start to grow,
تنشأ أنواع أخرى من الوسائل القريبة،
and then people can make a demand that's a poetic demand,
ثم يستطيع الناس أن يطلبوا طلبًا شاعريًا،
and the political demands that are necessary to wake up our cities,
والطلبات السياسية الضرورية لصحوة مدننا،
they also become very poetic.
تصبح أيضًا شاعرية جدًا.
JC: It makes perfect sense to me.
جون كوهين: إنه أمر معقول جدًا بالنسبة لي.
Theaster, thank you so much for being here with us today.
ثياستر، شكرًا جزيلًا لكونك هنا معنا اليوم.
Thank you. Theaster Gates.
شكرًا لك. ثياستر غيتس.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)